The Charles Shackford Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 19---1979; Series I; 6.3' (12 boxes)
  - Music by Charles Shackford, I.A
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D on three Jewish melodies for flute, clarinet, bassoon, violin, violoncello and harpsichord. -- 1975, c1976., 1 score (11], 33 sheets); 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 154)
      Holograph transparency signed, in pencil and ink.
      Dated: "New London, Conn., September 1975.".
      "Comissioned by Theodore J. Schultz IN MEMORY OF ISAAC KODIS (1894-1974) ALICE E. KODIS (1894-1973)"--p. [i].
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D. -- 1975, [c1976]., 6 parts; 16-32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D. -- 1975, [c1976]., 1 score (33 sheets); 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 156-157)
      Holograph (blueprint photocopy) signed, with black and red pencil and black and red ink holograph and manuscript markings.
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D on three Jewish melodies for flute, clarinet, bassoon, violin, violoncello and harpsichord. -- 1975, c1976., 1 score (33 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 158-159)
      C. 1: with red ink holograph and black and red pencil manuscript markings. Program notes laid in.
      C. 2: with pencil manuscript markings.
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D. -- 1975, [c1976]., 5 parts; 33 cm. (Box 8, Folder 160)
      1st movement only.
      Parts for clarinet, flute, violin, bassoon, and violoncello.
    - [Serenades, harpsichord, flute, clarinet, D] Serenade in D. -- 1975, [c1976]., 6 parts; 34 cm. (Box 8, Folder 161)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with red ink and red pencil holograph and pencil manuscript markings.
      "Proofed, CRS"--T.p., harpsichord part.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra (Sketches)], [9, 2] sheets, [21] p. of music; 28-35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra (Sketches)] Concerto for brass and symphonic ensemble in Bb. -- [1976, c1976]., 1 short score (29 p.); 34 cm. (Box 9, Folder 163)
      "Overture Concertante No. 2"--Caption.
      Includes sketches on t.p.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto for brass: score. -- [1976, c1977]., 1 score (46 p.): 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 164)
      With: [3] p. of sketches found among blank pages laid in.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto for brass and symphonic ensemble. -- 1976, c1977., 1 score ([i], 90 sheets); 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 165)
      "In memory of Walter Piston"--p. [i].
      "Concerto for brass, Masters of Score. Corrected 6/27/78"--Container.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto for brass and symphonic ensemble. -- 1976, c1977., 21 parts; 32-36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 166-167)
      Full set of parts.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra], [2] sheets of music; 22 x 28. (Box 9, Folder 168)
      Holograph (photocopy) with red ink markings.
      Corrections to masters of score.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto. -- 1976, [c1977]., 1 score (27 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 169)
      "Correction Copy"--p. 1
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto for brass and symphonic ensemble. -- 1976, c1977., 1 score (90 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 170)
      Program notes laid in.
    - [Concerto, brasses, orchestra] Concerto for brass and symphonic ensemble. -- 1976, c1977., 21 parts; 33-36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 171-173, Box 10)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with red ink holograph markings in piccolo part.
    - [Eclogue], 1 score (10 p.); 37 cm. (Box 10, Folder 174)
      Holograph in pencil with black and red ink markings.
      For two saxophones, harp, and 4 violoncellos.
      Duration: 10:37.
    - [Eclogue] Eclogue. -- c1976., 1 score (12 sheets); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 175)
      "New London 14 July 1976".
    - [Eclogue] Eclogue. -- 1976, [c1976]., 7 parts; 32 cm. (Box 10, Folder 175)
    - [Eclogue] Eclogue: for alto and tenor saxophones, four violoncellos and harp. -- c1976., 1 score (12 p.); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 176)
      C. 1: t.p. with artwork; "IN MEMORY of Kathryn Nason Piston"--p. (i].
      C. 2: "Uncorrected"--p. 1.
      C. 3: "Correction Copy"--p. 1, with red ink markings.
    - [Eclogue] Eclogue. -- 1976, [c1976]., 7 parts; 32-33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 177)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with pencil markings.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)], 1 score ([21] p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 178)
      3rd movement in short score format. In later versions, 3rd and 4th movements joined as one movement.
      Duration, 2nd movement: 4:56.; 4th movement: 3:50.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)] String quartet no. 1 in A. -- c1977., 1 score ([1], 26 p.); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 179)
      "Written for the Berkshire Quartet (Urico Rossi, violin, Abraham Skernick, viola, Fritz Magg, cello)."--p. [i].
      Dated: "New London, 3 August, 1977".
      Comissioned by dedicatee.
      "First performed at Music Mountain, Falls Village, Connecticut, September 3, 1977."--p. [i].
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)] Quartet in A. -- 1977, [c1977]., 4 parts; 31-33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 180)
      Manuscript transparency in ink with black and red pencil markings.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)] Quartet in A. -- 1977, [c1977]., 1 score (26 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 181)
      Holograph (blueprint photocopy) signed, with red ink holograph and red pencil manuscript markings.
      Holograph "Errata" note laid in with c. 1.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)] String Quartet no. 1 in A. -- c1977., 1 score (26 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1, A (Sketches)] Quartet in A. -- 1977, [c1977]., 4 parts; 33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 183)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with markings in pencil.
    - Adonai khakartani vateida (Box 10, Folder 183)
      See: Psalm 139.
    - [Birthday greeting for Barney] Birthday greeting for "Barney". -- c1978., 1 sheet of music; 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 184)
      Text: Proverbs II, 13, 19, 21, 23.
      "Birthday greeting for Barney (Rear Admiral William Sieglaff retired) for his 70th birthday 6 July 1978"--Container.
    - O Lord, thou hast searched me and known me (Box 10, Folder 184)
      See: Psalm 139
    - [Psalm 139 (Sketches)], [4] p., [1] sheet of music; 35-37 cm. (Box 10, Folder 185)
      Holograph in pencil and ink.
    - [Psalm 139 (Sketches)] Psalm 139: short score. -- [c1978]., 1 short score (14 [i.e. 15] p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 186)
      Hebrew and English words.
    - [Psalm 139. Text], [5] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 10, Folder 186)
      Text in Hebrew and English.
      "Belmont Beth-El. Concert 4/7/58 "--Note laid in.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139: for baritone, mixed chorus, and chamber orchestra: Verses 1, 2, 6-10, 23, 24. -- 1977-1978, c1978., 1 score (57 sheets); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 187)
      For solo baritone, chorus (SATB), and chamber orchestra.
      Dated: "New London, 12 January 1978".
      Commissioned by Cantica Hebraica of New York.
      With t.p. and dedication sheets laid in.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139. -- [c1978]., 1 vocal score (23 sheets); 32 cm. (Box 10, Folder 188)
      Manuscript transparency.
      Solo baritone and chorus parts with instrumental cues.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139. -- [c1978]., 12 parts; 22-23 cm. (Box 10, Folder 189)
      Full set of orchestra parts.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139. -- 1977-1978, [c1978]., 1 score (57 [i.e. 114] sheets); 22 x 30 cm. (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139: for baritone, mixed chorus and chamber orchestra. -- 1977-1978, c1978., 1 score (57 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 191)
      Holograph (blueprint photocopy) signed, with red ink markings.
      "Correction Copy"--T.p.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 139: for baritone, mixed chorus and chamber orchestra. -- 1977-1978, c1978., 1 vocal score; (23 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 192)
      Manuscript (blueprint photocopy) with red ink holograph and red pencil markings.
      Solo baritone and chorus parts.
    - [Psalm 139] Psalm 193: for baritone, mixed chorus and chamber orchestra. -- 1977-1978, c1978., 1 score ([ii], 57 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 193-194)
      T.p. signed, in pencil.
      "Written for Cantica Hebraica of New York"--p. [i].
      2 copies, with p. [i, ii] from different masters.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C. Vivace (Sketches)], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 195)
      "4th movement scetch of mm. 427-502 (incorporated in completed 1st copy)"--Note.
    - [Quartets, no. 2, C. Allegro], [1] sheet of music; 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 196)
      Holograph transparency in ink with manuscript pencil markings.
      Incomplete master sheet of score.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C] String quartet in C. -- [1979]. (Box 11, Folder 197)
      Contains 1st, 2nd (incomplete), and 4th movements.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C] String quartet in C. -- 1979., 1 score (21, 19 sheets); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 198)
      Holograph transparency signed, in ink (1st movement); holograph transparency (photocopy) signed, with ink and pencil manuscript markings (4th movement).
      Includes opening of 2nd movement on p. 21, 1st movement.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C] String quartet in C. -- 1979., 4 parts; 32-36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 199)
      Manuscript transparency in ink
      1st and 4th movements.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C] String quartet in C. -- 1979., 1 score (21, 19 p.); 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 200-201)
      Reproduction of transparencies.
      Commissioned by the Berkshire String Quartet.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C] String quartet in C. -- 1979., 4 parts; 33-36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 202)
      Manuscript (photocopy).
  - Music by Others, Arranged by Charles Shackford, I.B
    - [Hertz und Mund und That und Leben. Jesus bleibet meine Freude; arr.] Jesu, joy of man's desiring / J.S. Bach / [arranged by Charles Shackford. -- 19--]., Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 part; 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 203)
      Clarinet part.
    - Jesu, joy of man's desiring (Box 11, Folder 203)
      See: Hertz und Mund und That und Leben. Jesus bleibet meine Freude; arr.
    - [Pomp and circumstance, no. 1; arr.] [Arranged by Charles Shackford. -- 194- (?).], Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934; [1] sheet of music; 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 204)
      For Piano.
      Text by unknown author added.
    - [Son of God; arr.] Once in royal David's city / [arranged by Charles Shackford. -- 19--]., Gauntlett, Henry John; 1 vocal score ([1] sheet); 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 205)
      Holograph with typescript text.
      Words by Cecil Frances Alexander.
    - [Saudades do Brazil. No 7. Corcovado; arr. (Sketches)], Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; [3] sheets of music; 32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 206)
    - [Saudades do Brazil. No 7. Corcovado; arr.] Saudades do Brazil: VII corcovado / Darius Milhaud; bassoon and piano arrangement by Charles Shackford. -- [194-]., Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 206)
      Holograph signed, in ink with red pencil markings.
      "For Private Use Only"--p. [1].
    - [Saudades do Brazil. No 7. Corcovado; arr.] Saudades do Brazil: VII corcovado / Darius Milhaud; arranged for bassoon and piano by Charles Shackford. -- [194-]., Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974 (Box 11, Folder 206)
      "For private use only"--T.p.
    - [Post eighty marching song; arr.] Post eighty marching song / words by W. Bradford Grove music arranged by Charles Shackford. -- [195-]., Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; 1 chorus score ([1] sheet); 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 207)
      For unison and 2 part chorus.
      Music by (?).
      Boy scout material laid in.
  - Music by Others, I.C
    - [Tower of Babel] The tower of Babel: cantata for mixed voices, piano and percussion / by Nevett Bartow. -- Delaware Water Gap, Pa.: Shawnee Press, Inc., c1969., Bartow, Nevett; 1 score (40 p.); 27 cm. (Box 11, Folder 208)
      Letter from Bartow to Charles Shackford laid in.
    - [Cantata on psalm 100 new] Cantata on 'Psalm 100 new' / Lincoln A. Baxter. -- c1979., Baxter, Lincoln; 1 score (46 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 209)
      Dated: "November 30, 1979 Philadelphia".
      "Comissioned by the Mt. Herman School on the occasion of its centennial celebration"--T.p.
      Dedication: "To Charles Reeve Shackford, 1918-1979".
      Holograph inscription on t.p.
      Letter from Baxter to Jane Shackford laid in.
    - Psalm 100 new, Baxter, Lincoln (Box 11, Folder 209)
      See: Cantata on psalm 100 new.
    - [Gesänge, women's voices, horns (2), harp, op. 17] Gesänge für Frauenchor, op. 17 / Johannes Brahms. -- [1860]., Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; 1 part [4 p.]; 32 cm. (Box 11, Folder 210)
      Manuscript in Charles Shackford's hand in ink.
      Part for horns.
    - [Child this day is born] A child this day is born: a Christmas carol for four-part chorus of women's voices / William Herrmann. -- [New York]: G. Schirmer. -- c1966., Herrmann, William; 1 vocal score (4 p.); 27 cm. (Box 11, Folder 211)
      For woments chorus (SSAA).
      Dedication: "For the Wellesley College Choir".
      Inscription: "To Charles with warm greetings. Bill"--p. 1.
    - [Mathis der Maler. Vorspiel. Vocal score] Mathis der Maler: Oper in sieben Bildern: Vorspiel Engelkonzert / Paul Hindemith. -- Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, c1935., Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; 1 vocal score (p.IV-VII, X-XII); 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 212)
      Photocopy.
      Pl. no.: B.S.S. 34002.
    - [Symphonische Tänze. Langsam. Selections] Excerpts from "Symphonic dances" by Paul Hindemith: #1 from the first movement, clarinets and bassoons as accompanying instruments: bridge and second theme group. -- [c1938]., Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; 1 score (10, 5 [i.e. 7] p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - [Latitudes] Latitudes. -- 1978., Wadif, John P.; 1 score (19 sheets); 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 214)
      For clarinet and violin (?).
      "John P Wadif (?), April 1978"--At end.
    - [Ring der Niebelungen. Götterdämmerung] Götterdämmerung / von Richard Wagner; English translation by Frederick Jameson; version française par Alfred Ernst: V. I. -- Edition Eulenburg, [19--]., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; 1 score [12] sheets); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 215)
      Photcopies of assorted p.
      "Götterdämmerung Magic Potion Motive, full & vocal scores"--Container.
    - [Ring der Niebelungen. Götterdämmerung. Vocal score] Götterdämmerung / von Richard Wagner; English translation by H. & F. Corder; vollständigen Klavierauszug von R. Kleinmichel. -- New York: G. Schirmer, [18--?]., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; 1 vocal score ([10] sheets); 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 215)
      From same container as previous item.
      Plate no.: 23263.
      Envelope with notes laid in.
  - Music by Charles Shackford, Oversize Materials, I.D
    - [Sonatinas, oboe, harp] Sonatina, oboe & harp. -- 1943., 1 score (12 p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 216)
      "Paul Hindemith's Class at Yale 1943"--T.p.
    - [Sonatinas, oboe, harp] Sonatina, oboe & harp. -- 1943., 1 part; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - [Overture concertante (Sketches)], [5] sheets of music; 30 x 47 cm. (Box 12, Folder 217)
      "Overture Concertant[e]"--Sheet [4].
    - [Overture concertante] Overture concertante. -- c1974., 1 score (15 p.); 44 cm. (Box 12, Folder 218)
      Holograph in pencil and ink with typescript caption, tempo, and copyright.
      p. 15: pencil on transparency.
      With: Quartets, strings, no. 2, C (Sketches) (1979), verso of p. 15.
    - [Overture concertante] Overture concertante. -- c1974., 1 score (14 sheets); 44 cm. (Box 12, Folder 219)
      Holograph (photocopy on transparency).
    - [Overture concertante] Overture concertante for concert band. -- c1974., 1 score (96 p.), bound; 44 cm. (Box 12, Folder 220-221)
      C. 1: with red and black pencil manuscript markings.
      C. 2: hardcover binding.
      "IN MEMORY of my musical forebears of the family: Charles McCormick Reeve, Lilly Reeve, Mary Schley and their father Isaac VanDuzer Reeve, Brigadier General, U.S.A."--Inside cover.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C (Sketches)], 33, 19, 19, [5] sheets of music; 85 mm. [sic]-53 cm. (Box 12, Folder 222-223)
      Holograph in pencil with pencil and red ink manuscript markings.
      Includes sketches for third movement among sheets [1-5].
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 44 cm. (Box 12, Folder 218)
      Holograph transparency.
      With: Overture concertante (1974) (p. 15 of holograph master score) on versa.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C. Allegretto], 1 score (sheets 18-28, [19] sheets); 40 cm. (Box 12, Folder 224)
      2nd (incomplete) and 4th movements.
      Reproduction of pencil score.
      "Quartet in C. Material for Roger Blanc"--Container.
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 2, C. Allegro.], 1 score (20 [i.e. 25] sheets); 46 cm. (Box 12, Folder 225)
      Holograph (blueprint photocopy) signed.
      1st and 2nd (incomplete) movements
- Writings by Charles Shackford, 1945-1979; Series II; 1' (3 boxes)
  Writings are arranged alphabetically by title. As with the music, descriptions follow the order that conforms to a given work's development. Research materials, such as music and articles by others, are included as the last description under the title of the work to which they apply.
  - Called to be saints. -- 1967., 6 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Typescript (photocopy).
    Sermon.
    Dated: "Connecticut College, February 12, 1967."
  - [Casey Jones], 12 sheets; 21-28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Notes to paper given before Ariston (?), ca. 1970 (?).
  - [Casey Jones] [Research materials], 20 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Photocopies.
    Extracts from books and articles, with some pencil holograph notes.
  - A Christmas miracle. -- 1977., 9 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    "Ariston, 6 December 1977"--Caption.
  - A contribution to the history of parody technique / John Daniskas; [English translation by Charles Shackford]., 15 p.; 32 cm. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    "Tijdschrift voor Muziekwetenschap, Amsterdam, I (1948), 21-43."--p. 1.
  - A contribution to the history of parody technique / John Daniskas; English translation by Charles R. Shackford = Een bijdrage tot de beschiedenis der parodie-techniek [from] Tijdschrift voor muziekwetenschap., 21 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Published by Translations Center of Brooklyn College, Oct., 1974.
    Photocopy of Translations Center newsletter laid in.
  - 'Desperadoes' to play at beach., [1] sheet; 40 cm. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Clipping from: [The Day (?), New London, 1970].
  - Determination of pitches and interval sizes in ensemble string performance: a paper read by Charles R. Shackford at the fiftieth national meeting of the Acoustical Society of America, Providence, Rhode Island, December 15, 1955., 7 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Typescript with pencil and ink corrections.
    9 sheets; 28 cm.
    Typescript (photocopy) with pencil corrections.
  - Discussion and presentation of choral music of the late Renaissance. -- 1963., 3 sheets; 28-39 cm. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Typescript (photocopy and reproduction stencil).
    "For broadcast on channel 8, TV, 20 February, 1963"--Caption.
  - ["Imitatio" in Dufay's missa Se la face ay pale], [92] sheets; 19-32 cm. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Holograph in pencil and blue and red ink.
    Notes and drafts.
    Paper presented at the American Musicological Society meeting, Nov. 1, 1974.
  - ["Imitatio" in Dufay's missa Se la face ay pale], [41, 4], 3, 10, [2] sheets; 22-38 cm. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Holograph in pencil and holograph (photocopy).
    Notes and musical examples.
  - Some indications of "imitatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connecticut College. -- [1976]., 16 [i.e. 35] sheets; 12-28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Typescript and holograph in pencil with photocopies.
    Title varies between sheet 1 original and photocopy.
    Extra photocopies of sheets 1 and 1341 laid in.
  - "Imitatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connecticut College. -- [1976]., 16 [i.e. 19] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Typescript, photocopies of typescript.
  - "Imitatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connecticut College. -- [1976]., 15 [i.e. 15] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Typescript (photocopy) with typed, ink, and pencil corrections.
    Lacking sheets 7 and 16.
    Photocopy of item with sheets 7 and 16 laid in.
  - "Imitatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connecticut College. -- [1976]., 13 [i.e. 28] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Typescript and typescript (photocopy) with red ink and pencil corrections.
  - Some indications of "imitiatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connnecticut College. -- [1976]., 60 sheets; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Typescript (photocopy) with manuscript pencil markings.
    Letter from Lewis Lockwood to Charles Shackford with comments, and from Charles Shackford to Lockwood laid in.
  - Some indications of "imitiatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connnecticut College. -- [1976]., 10 [i.e. 17] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Typescript with blue and red ink and pencil corrections.
  - "Imitiatio" in Dufay's missa "Se la face ay pale" / Charles R. Shackford, Connecticut College. -- [1976]., 3 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Typescript with corrections (photopeopy).
    9 [i.e. 11] sheets; 28 cm.
    Typescript.
    [10] sheets; 28 cm.
    Typescript and holograph (photocopy).
    Holograph notes in pencil on sheet 1, verso.
  - [Research materials] (Box 14, Folder 17-21)
    3 folders of photocopied scores of music by others, musical examples, articles by others, extracts from books by others, and holograph notes.
  - An investigation of intonation in string performance. -- [1949]., 8 [i.e. 9] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    Typescript with holograph musical examples and pencil manuscript comments.
    "Walter Piston's comments on a proposal for thesis research topic sent in August 1949"--Container.
    [10] sheets; 10-28 cm.
    Manuscript in ink and pencil with holograph musical examples, diagrams, and notes.
    "Le Conbeillen--Comments on Shackford thesis"--Container.
  - Last night's concert: Liverpool Cathedral's organist presents widely-varied program., [1] sheet; 18 cm. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    Clipping from newspaper: [The Day], New London, April 24, 1967.
    Review of recital given by Noel Rawsthorne.
  - Lecture, Wellesley College. -- 1960., 29 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    On the perception of musical intervals.
  - Music in the liberal arts., 6 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    Holograph in pen.
    Notes for talk given at meeting of Twelve College
    Exchange, September 29, 1972 (?).
  - New course in choral singing. -- October, 1945., p. 4-5; 24 cm. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    In: Bennett [Junior College] Bulletin, V. II, no. 1, Millbrook, New York, October, 1945.
  - Notes for paper given by Charles Shackford at Ann Arbor, 1954., 12 [i.e. 15 sheets]; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    On intonation in ensemble string performance
    "A.M.S., Ann Arbor, Dec. 1954"--Sheet 1.
  - Overture Concertante: a composer's thoughts about one of his works. -- 1978., 5 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    "Ariston, 3 October 1978"--Caption.
  - Paper for A.M.S. meeting. -- March 1961., 15 [i.e. 19] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 29)
    On the perception and measurement of musical intervals.
  - [Paul Hindemith's Unterweisung im Tonsatz. -- 1972], [16] p.; 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Paul Hindemith['s] Unterweisung im Tonsatz: III Übungsbuch für den dreistimmigen Satz. -- [1972]., 4 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 30)